robhunter

software engineering professional

Self-motivated, highly adaptable, and organized software engineering professional with eight years of experience specializing in automated build and test systems. Outstanding troubleshooting and problem solving skills, with a proven ability to identify and solve root-cause issues.

CORE COMPETENCIES

- Quality assurance and control
- Commercialization engineering
- Software build master
- Software design and development
- Process management
- Team management

TECHNICAL COMPETENCIES

Programming

- C/C++
- C#
- Python
- Pascal
- VB6, VB.NET
- Java
- Batch Scripting
- VBScript

Technologies

- Build & Test Automation
- Source Control
- Continuous Integration
- Windows Installer
- Software License Protection
- SharePoint
- Virtualization
- Wikis

Processes

- Scrum
- Lean
- TDD
- Agile Testing
- Usability Testing
- Software Compliance
- Commercial Deployment
- Trade Compliance

TOOLS EXPERIENCE

Quality Assurance Tools

- TestComplete
- QTP/WinRunner
- MSTest with dotCover
- NUnit with NCover

Build Tools

- TeamCity
- TFS TeamBuild
- CruiseControl.NET
- MSBuild
- NAnt
- FinalBuilder

SCCM/ALM

- TFS
- StarTeam
- Git

Development Environments

- Visual Studio
- C++ Builder
- Delphi
- Eclipse

Installation Authoring

- WIX
- Wise Installation Studio
- Inno Setup
- InstallShield
- NSIS

Other

- Morae
- Reprise License Manager
- Aladdin HASP
- VMWare Workstation

EDUCATION

University of Waterloo, Canada

B.ASc. Computer Engineering (Co-op), 2006

CO-OP WORK EXPERIENCE

Control Systems Software Developer ATS Automation Tooling Systems Inc.

2005 (8 months) - Cambridge, ON

Machine vision software development in C++/C

Payload Assistant Canadian Space Agency

2004 (4 months) - St. Hubert, QC

 Canadian telemetry project for International Space Station in C++/VB.NET

Assistant Building Systems Engineer Dufferin-Peel Catholic District School Board

2003 (4 months) – Mississauga, ON

- Automated backup of HVAC control programs using C++/Win32 API
- Warehouse database project in FileMaker Pro

Software Developer Synexus Global Inc.

2002/2003 (8 months) - Niagara Falls, ON

 Hydroelectric power generation decision support software development in C++

CONTACT

rphunter@gmail.com

http://www.linkedin.com/in/rphunter

rob**hunter**

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Commercialization Engineering Process Lead
Schlumberger Canada Limited (Schlumberger Water Services)
* Currently employed in this position

November 2010 - Present Waterloo, ON

Responsible for coordinating all commercial deployment activities for all software products developed in Waterloo office, in this role I am also working to improve software quality in all aspects of the Agile quadrants, while enforcing stricter commercialization deadlines. Emphasis has been on introducing Agile processes and tools, empowering co-workers, strengthening our internship program, and shipping software to schedule. This role includes managing the test team, maintaining the build and testing infrastructure, and overseeing the SDLC.

- Incorporated Agile development and testing into new development projects; piloting Scrum, TDD, usability testing, and UI test automation; evaluated and chose supporting tools
- Simplified build templates to support two primary configurations: fast developer-facing continuous integration builds with BVTs, and full "release candidate" rebuilds that run all automated tests and can be promoted to release externally
- Product owner for components shared across product portfolio including license protection controls, automatic update notification, and application analytics

QA/QC Coordinator for Water Services Software Schlumberger Canada Limited (Schlumberger Water Services)

April 2008 - November 2010 Waterloo, ON

In this role, in addition to my previous responsibilities of Build and Deployment Specialist, I was given the additional responsibility of managing the QA/QC team, which included a tester, a technical writer, and a co-op student. Through 2009 and 2010, I also co-managed the three member technical support team with the sales manager. Additionally, I took on the management of two software development projects.

- Managed QA/QC team, and initiated co-op student recruitment for both the QA/QC and development teams
- Managed technical support team and handled escalated client installation, deployment, and licensing issues
- Introduced continuous integration systems and improved build performance
- Refactored installation packages to improve user experience and significantly reduce client-reported installation issues
- Led a project to replace the licensing protection across all software products developed in Waterloo, developed the original design and prototypes, and managed the development and integration
- Managed an out-sourced project to deploy multiple software applications in a streamlined manner through a chained installation

Software Build and Deployment Specialist Schlumberger Canada Limited (Schlumberger Water Services)

May 2006 - April 2008 Waterloo, ON

I was hired out of university by Schlumberger for the new build and deployment specialist role. This role was originally to manually integrate software build components into installation packages, and act as a collaboration point of contact between the software development, marketing, and sales departments for all commercialization activities. I broadened the role to include source control management, automation of component integration, automated build scheduling, and contributing to the inhouse SDLC processes.

- Responsible for the release of all software products
- Updated release processes to include trade compliance procedures, license auditing, and review of EULA
- Restructured the source control configuration to improve branching
- Performed all independent builds of water services software products
- Introduced automation into the software build process